Guide to the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Editorial Records 1969-1988 MS 3009-RG 34
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Editorial Records
1969-1988
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 34
10 Linear feet in 11 record cartons
Sports Illustrated launched in August 1954. The Editorial Records are primarily correspondence from senior editorial staff to place articles or excerpts from outside writers. There is a small amount of administrative records.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts and are located in box R65.
Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible.
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series based on the hierarchy of staff:
Series I. Managing Editor Mark Mulvoy Copy of Strategic Plan
Series II. Assistant Managing Editor and Senior Editor Ray Cave Files
Series III. Senior Editor Patricia Ryan Files
Series IV. Associate Editor Joseph Carroll Correspondence
Historical Note
Sports Illustrated (SI) launched on August 16, 1954 as a weekly magazine with Managing Editor Sidney James and Publisher Harry Phillips.
According to an unsigned capsule history in the General Files of the publishing and business records (MS 3009-RG 35), Time Inc. cofounder and president Henry R. Luce asked Executive Vice President Howard Black to come up with new publishing venture ideas. Black's May 21, 1953 letter to Luce contained a paragraph reading: "A Sports Weekly -- everything in sports -- hunting, fishing, boating. this would be a picture magazine -- 10 cents a copy." By June 1953, Time Inc. set up a department to develop this magazine.
The "Editorial Notes" in the RG 35 General Files state that SI was the first Time Inc. magazine to include bylines. It started with well-known sports writers. Later it incorporated articles from famous authors such as "[William] Faulkner and Catherine Drinker Bowen on the Derby," and "Robert Frost on the All-Star Game." Great sports writers also started their careers as early SI staff writers including Robert Creamer and "Tex" Maule.
For the majority of Time Inc.'s existence, the company maintained a strict separation of editorial from the publishing and business side of each magazine, colloquially called the separation of "church" (editorial) and "state" (publishing). Editorial includes the editors, researchers, and art department. The editorial side reported up to the editor-in-chief and the publishing/business side reported up to the corporate business executive which was the president prior to 1960 and the chief executive officer after. Henry Luce structured Time Inc. this way so that the business side could not (in theory) influence the editorial content of the publications. For example, the advertising sales people could not interfere with a magazine's decision to run an article on the dangers of cigarette smoking, even though it might mean losing millions of dollars in tobacco ads.
Citations:
Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, 10 June 2016.
Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Publishing and Business Records, MS 3009-RG 35, New-York Historical Society.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Information about the history of Sports Illustrated and additional records from the editorial offices can be found in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and the Time Inc. Annex Files (MS 3009-RG 39). Records from the publishing and business offices is in the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated Publishing and Business Records (MS 3009-RG 35). RG 35 also includes a 1954 editorial staff list in the Divisional History folder.
Scope and Contents
The Sports Illustrated Editorial Records are primarily correspondence from senior editorial staff to place articles or excerpts from outside writers. Outside writers include those from other magazines (sometimes other Time Inc. magazines), freelancers, and some amateurs. Files do not always have correspondence from the writer and may only contain internal correspondence regarding their article or excerpt. Topics include story ideas, submissions, the logistics of publishing accepted articles, and payment amounts. There is a small amount of administrative records. The majority of correspondence comes from Senior Editor Patricia "Pat" Ryan. Her records also include the Text Department's financial records. This seems to be the department in charge of reviewing submitted manuscripts.
American periodicals -- History; Authors and publishers -- United States.; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Journalists -- United States.; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Reporters and reporting -- United States.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History; Cave, Ray, 1929-; Ryan, Pat, 1938-2013
- Series I. Managing Editor Mark Mulvoy Copy of Strategic Plan, 1988; 0.1 Linear feet in 1 folder
  Scope and Contents
  Mark Mulvoy's files on Sports Illustrated comprise his copy of the strategic plan for 1987 to 1997. Its contents include the Mission Statement, Overview, Changes in the Environment, Strategy, and Financial Review.
  This item was found with other Sports Illustrated materials to be filed.
  Arrangement
  The series is a single item.
  - Strategic Plan 1987-1997, 1988 (Offsite-box 4103, Folder 1)
- Series II. Assistant Managing Editor and Senior Editor Ray Cave Files, 1969-1970; 0.5 Linear feet in 29 folders
  Biographical Note
  Ray Cave started at Sports Illustrated as a reporter in 1959, was promoted from a senior editor to Assistant Managing Editor in November 1970, and rose to deputy to Managing Editor Andre Laguerre. After a "stint as Acting Editorial Director of all Time Inc. publications", Editor-in-Chief Hedley Donovan appointed Cave as Time Assistant Managing Editor in 1976. The next year, he became Time Managing Editor and served in this role through 1985. From 1986 to 1988, Cave served in several corporate editorial roles before resigning from Time Inc. in 1988.
  Citations:
  Davidson, Ralph. "A Letter from the Publisher." Time, October 10, 1977.
  "The Hottest Editor." Farewells, Time Life Alumni Society, TLASconnect. http://www.tlasconnect.com/farewells.html
  "The Media Business; A Top Editorial Executive Is Forced Out at Time Inc." New York Times, November 18, 1988. http://www.nytimes.com/1988/11/18/business/the-media-business-a-top-editorial-executive-is-forced-out-at-time-inc.html
  Records from Ray Cave span from a year when he served as a Sports Illustrated senior editor then an assistant managing editor and primarily contain correspondence to place articles or excerpts from outside writers. Outside writers include those from other magazines (sometimes other Time Inc. magazines), freelancers, and some amateurs. Files do not always have correspondence from the writer and may only contain internal correspondence regarding their article or excerpt. Topics include story ideas, submissions, the logistics of publishing accepted articles, and payment amounts. The correspondence is similar to that in Patricia Ryan's and Joseph Carroll's files.
  Records remain in their original order with administrative and personal files before correspondence and correspondence organized alphabetically.
  - Expenses Statements, 1969 (Offsite-box 4102, Folder 1)
  - Budget [empty], 1970 (Offsite-box 4102, Folder 2)
  - Personal, 1970 (Offsite-box 4102, Folder 3)
  - Copyright Assignments [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R65)
  - Correspondence: A-Z, 1970 (Offsite-box 4102, Folder 4-28)
    Folders for Q and U are empty.
- Series III. Senior Editor Patricia Ryan Files, 1970-1974; 9 Linear feet in 10 record cartons
  Patricia "Pat" Ryan joined Time Inc. in 1960 as a secretary at Sports Illustrated (SI). In 1971 SI promoted her to senior editor after holding positions as a researcher and writer. While the 1971 and 1974 SI masthead lists her as a senior editor, Ryan signs as Text Department Editor, and is also addressed as the articles editor. Her duties included negotiations with contract writers for articles and publishers for book excerpts. Richard Munro obliquely states in his SI September 4, 1972 letter from the publisher that Ryan was the first woman to rise to Senior Editor at SI.
  In her Inside Time Inc. 1984 interview, she recounts the argument she had with SI Managing Editor Andre Laguerre over her byline after her 1966 promotion to staff writer. Ryan wanted her byline to be "Pat Ryan" rather than "Patricia" since she "felt that a woman's byline would be suspect in a man's world." In fact, she is addressed as "Mr. Ryan" in a number of letters in her correspondence. Laguerre agreed to the byline, but still listed her as "Patricia" on the masthead.
  Ryan joined People as a senior editor in 1978 and was swiftly promoted to Assistant Managing Editor, Executive Editor, then Managing Editor by March 1982. She was the second managing editor for People, and the first woman at Time Inc. in a top editorial position. According to a memoranda in Life Managing Editor Judith Daniels' files, Ryan was named Life Managing Editor in April 1987. She was fired in 1989 without an explanation though the The New York Times posits it was due to the rivalry between her partner and Time Inc. coworker Ray Cave and Editor-in-Chief Jason McManus.
  "Former Time Inc. editor dies at 75." Boothbay Register, December 31, 2013. https://www.boothbayregister.com/article/former-time-inc-editor-dies-75/26364.
  Kirkpatrick, David. "New M.E.s at PEOPLE and LIFE." f.y.i., March 29, 1982.
  Time Inc. Bio Files, MS 3009-RG 2, New-York Historical Society.
  Weber, Bruce. "Patricia Ryan, a Managing Editor at Time Inc., Dies at 75." The New York Times, December 31, 2013. https://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/01/business/media/patricia-ryan-75-an-editor-at-time-inc-dies.html.
  Records from Patricia Ryan primarily contain correspondence to place articles or excerpts from outside writers. Outside writers include those from other magazines (sometimes other Time Inc. magazines), freelancers, and some amateurs. Files do not always have correspondence from the writer and may only contain internal correspondence regarding their article or excerpt. Topics include story ideas, submissions, the logistics of publishing accepted articles, and payment amounts. The correspondence is similar to that in Ray Cave's and Joseph Carroll's files.
  Besides the correspondence to outside writers, Ryan's files include copyright assignments as part of the correspondence files and memoranda to Sports Illustrated Managing Editor Roy Terrell. Her records also include financial records of the Text Department which seems to have reviewed submitted manuscripts.
  Ryan's files are organized mainly chronologically then alphabetically and there is some repetition of names in each year. Correspondence contains general A to Z files followed by specific folders for individuals. It is possible materials from individuals with a specific folder are also in the general folder.
  The records are organized alphabetically by Correspondence, Memoranda, and Text Department with this arrangement imposed by the archivist. The Correspondence is kept in the original arrangement scheme of alphabetical runs grouped chronologically. There is some crossover of years in each run. For example, while the first run is "1972 and Before", it has a few files with materials dating from 1973.
  - Correspondence: 1972 and Earlier (Box -, Folder -)
  - Correspondence: A-L, 1972 (Offsite-box 4103, Folder 2-19)
  - Correspondence: M-Z, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 1-15)
  - Correspondence: Allen: Philosophy of Coaching [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Allen, Woody, circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Bell, Upton: Where the Bodies Buried, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Bowen, Ezra, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Brown, Sandy: Croquet, 1971 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Bruns: Milt Kahn [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Butwin, David: Bowling, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Carter, Rubin: The Sixteenth Round, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Casler, Conrad: Street-racing Scene, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Chapin, Kim, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Chatham: Schaadt [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Cope, Myron, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Cronley, Jay, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Dickerson, George: High-Low Poker, circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Dryden, Ken: Nader Research, 1971 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Duffy, Bob, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Eliot, Alex: Eton Story, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Elon, Amos: National Israeli Walk, 1971 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Feldkamp, Fred: Head Family, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Fischer, Bobby: Chess, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Fowles, John: Cricket, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Francis, Dick, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Gammon, Clive, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Gilbert, Bil, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Harrison, Jim, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Hathaway, Paul, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Henkin, Harmon: Clark Fork Fishing [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Hersey, John, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Higdon, Hal: David Pain, 1973 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Hirschberg, Al: Haiti Baseballs, circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Hjortsberg, William, 1972 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: Hoagland, Edward: Lynn Rogers and Black Bears, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4104, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence: Jerome, John: Cross-Country Ski Essay, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Johnston, Dick, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Jordan, Pat, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Kay, John: Numbers Game, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Kinnel, Galway: Virginia Wade, 1972? (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Kobler: Las Vegas Junkets, circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Lombardy, William: Chess Championship, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Maddocks, Melvin, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Mailer, Norman: Frazier, 1972? (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: McGuane, Tom, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: McIlvanney, Hugh, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Metcalf, John, 1971 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Miles, Dick, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Peter: Burke Mountain Academy, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Mitchell, Carleton, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Moore, Kenny, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Myslenski, Skip, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Needleman: Thesis, 1972? (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: O'Neil: Caddying at the Open [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Orr, Bobby: Instructional [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Perry, Gaylord: Spitter [empty], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Plimpton, George, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Rapoport, Roger, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Roth, Philip: The Great American Novel, 1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 24-25)
  - Correspondence: Sheehan: Senior Olympic Travelers, 1972? (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Smith, Adam: Yoga Tennis, 1972? (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Telander, Rick, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Tippette, Giles: Saturday's Children, 1971 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Weeks, Morris: Boatman Van Ost, 1970 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Yates, Brock, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: 1973 (Box -, Folder -)
  - Correspondence: Assignment of Copyrights, 1973 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: A-D, 1973 (Offsite-box 4105, Folder 33-39)
  - Correspondence: D-N, 1973 (Offsite-box 4106, Folder 1-18)
  - Correspondence: P-Z, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 1-16)
  - Correspondence: Bell, Upton: Where the Bodies Buried [empty], circa 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Blount, Roy, Jr.: Pittsburgh Steelers [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Offsite-box R65)
  - Correspondence: Blount, Roy, Jr.: Pro Football Club, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Brown, Sandy: Croquet [empty], circa 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Bruns, Bill: Milt Kahn (Milt's Mirror), 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Cantwell, Robert, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Chapin, Kim, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Chatham, Russell, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Conroy, Frank: Bob Francis, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Cope, Myron, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Creamer, Bob: Babe Ruth, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Crews, Harry, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Cronley, Jay, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Dillard, Annie: Letter from the Blue Ridge, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Duffy, Bob, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Dunn, Jim: West Coast Run, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Gerber, Dan, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 32-33)
  - Correspondence: Gilbert, Bil, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 34-35)
  - Correspondence: Gilbert, Sam: Bill Walton, 1973 (Offsite-box 4107, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Goodman, George aka Adam Smith, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Gutkind, Lee, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Harris, Sherwood: Voisin Flying Machine, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Harrison, Jim, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Havemann, Ernest, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Hjortsberg, William, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Hoagland, Edward, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Holland, Gerald, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Holway, John, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Johnston, Dick, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Jordan, Pat, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Lombardy, William: Chess Championship, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Maddocks, Melvin, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Mano, Keith: Softball, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: McCabe, Susan: Hartack Story, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: McGuane, Tom, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: McIlvanney, Hugh, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Miles, Dick [empty], 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Mitchell, Carleton, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Moore, Kenny, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Moses, Sam: Kenny Roberts, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Needleman: Thesis [empty], circa 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Nicklaus, Jack, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Orr, Bobby: Instructional, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Perkins, Steve: Archie Stone, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Plimpton, George, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Reed, J. D., 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Richler, Mordechai: Maxi Burger [empty], circa 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Robertson, Bob: Crosswords/Ted Weed, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Schulian, John, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Smith, Mason: Upcoming Story, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Sutton-Smith, Brian: Vive Essay, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Telander, Rick, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Tippette, Giles, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Tronquet, P. J.: Fishing on Cape Flattery, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Tyler: Perfect Liberty, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Valdene, Guy de la, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: Whall, Hugh, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: White, Ellington: Lake Drummond, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Willeford, Charles, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Wills, Garry: Sport and Religion, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Wolf, Dave: Duane Bobick, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Writers, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Yates, Brock, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: Zimmerman: Falconers Hunting Meet, 1973 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: 1974 (Box -, Folder -)
  - Correspondence: A-C, 1974 (Offsite-box 4108, Folder 46-51)
  - Correspondence: D-M, 1974 (Offsite-box 4109, Folder 1-17)
  - Correspondence: M-Z, 1974 (Offsite-box 4110, Folder 1-21)
  - Correspondence: Assignment of Copyright, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Blount, Roy: Contract: Pittsburgh Steelers, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Brome, Chuch: Gold House, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Butcher, Grace, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Cantwell, Robert, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Chatham, Russell, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Crews, Harry [empty], 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Cronley, Jay, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 8)
    Includes audiovisual material.
    1 audiocassette: analog, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: "Whelan's Nature Series." The tape is detached.
  - Correspondence: Eastlake, William: Indian Rodeos, 1974 (Offsite-box 4111, Folder 9)